# Kelly Ann Marshall

## Web Development + Web Design + Print Design + Photography

BFA Photography, MSc Information Technology (Merit) +44 (0)7906 117 249 kelly\_ann\_marshall@yahoo.com

# Summary

Talented frontend developer, print and web designer with over 29 years of professional experience who is self-motivated, client-centric, creative, insightful and versatile. Adept at innovating user experience for web applications. Exceptional interpersonal skills and is efficient, organised, resourceful, flexible, reliable and willing to listen and contribute with clients and team members. Available for contract or permanent positions based in Glasgow City Centre or 100% remote.

# Skills

- HTML(5)
- CSS(3) / SASS / LESS
- JavaScript / ES6 / jQuery
- Node / Grunt / Gulp / Webpack
- Angular / Vue
- Jasmine / Karma / Jest / Cypress
- Git / Bitbucket / SVN
- Jekyll / Joomla / Wordpress
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Balsamiq / Figma / AdobeXD
- Responsive Web Design
- · Progressive Enhancement
- W3C Standards & Accessibility
- Cross-Browser Compatibility
- Google Analytics

# **Professional Experience**

Idox Group (acquired thinkWhere in Oct 2021) – Glasgow, Scotland (Aug 2020 - present) Senior Developer

Working as part of an agile development team with a focus on design and UI development of groundMapper, a fully-featured cloud service GIS data application.

Programs and languages used: Angular, Typescript, OpenLayers, Bootstrap, Cypress, AWS, pgAdmin, Docker, Figma, AdobeXD, Balsamiq, Git, Jira

#### Selected Accomplishments:

- Wireframing, UI design and front-end development of advanced search functionality, split-screen map / data views, and bespoke forestry data management features.
- Development and delivery of new administrative features for groundMapper, including account, project and user management and permissions.
- UI design and front-end development of Eurogeographics Open Maps for Europe website, a resource for official European map, geospatial and land information.
- · Upgraded legacy client-side code and dependencies to improve security and accessibility.

VisitScotland – Edinburgh, Scotland (Aug 2018 - Feb 2020) *UI Developer* 

I worked as part of an internal development team tasked with a major re-platforming project for VisitScotland's flagship website, www.visitscotland.com.

Programs and languages used: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, VueJS, JavaScript / ES6, MapboxGL, Node, Webpack, Gulp, Cypress, VSCode, BloomReach Experience CMS, Freemarker, Bitbucket, Jira

#### Selected Accomplishments:

- Created proof of concept interactive tourism destination maps focussed on accessibility and with rich features including filtering and sorting destination product and event data on name, product type, rating, price and date.
- Worked with UX, Design and Software Engineering teams to create complex itinerary CMS templates integrating destination product data and itinerary maps.

# **Previous Experience**

Peninsula Business Services - Glasgow, Scotland (Aug 2017 - May 2018)

Front-End Developer

Arnold Clark - Glasgow, Scotland (Feb 2014 - May 2017)

Front-End Developer

The University of Glasgow - Glasgow, Scotland (Oct 2012 - Nov 2013)

Web Content Officer

The University of Glasgow - Glasgow, Scotland (Oct 2011 - Sep 2012)

Web Developer / Research Assistant

Admit One - New York, NY (Feb 2008 - Sep 2010)

Print and Web Designer

Henry M. Jackson Foundation - Bethesda, MD (Nov 2002 - Nov 2007)

Print and Web Designer

LADO International College – Washington, DC (Feb 1999 - Dec 2000)

Print and Web Designer

Channing Bete - South Deerfield, MA (Jun 1996 - Jan 1999)

Advertising Designer

Freelance Designer - New York, NY (May 1994 - May 1996)

**Graphic Designer** 

Digital Stock Connection - Rockville, MD (Jun 1993 - May 1994)

Digital Retoucher

Elegant Images – Towson, MD (Jun 1992 - Mar 1993)

Studio Portrait Photographer

## Education

University of Glasgow – Master of Science in Information Technology (Sep 2010 - Sep 2011) Areas of emphasis: Programming in Java, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, XML, HTML, CSS, Django, Python, Multimedia Systems, Software Project Management, Information Systems and Databases

Final Project and Dissertation: An web interface for the purchase of live event tickets featuring interactive venue maps built with SVG, JavaScript, PHP and MySQL

Activities: Postgraduate Student Representative

Maryland Institute, College of Art – Bachelor of Fine Arts in Photography (Sep 1989 - Jun 1993)

Areas of emphasis: B&W and colour photography and development, film and video production, photochemistry, alternative photo processes, studio lighting, 2D design, computer illustration, painting, drawing, sculpture, art history and the history of photography

Edinburgh Napier University – International Student Mobility, Photography (Sep 1991 - Dec 1991)

Areas of emphasis: Commercial B&W and colour photography and development, studio lighting, photojournalism, medium and large format photography

### Portfolio / References

Available upon request. Online portfolio is available at https://kellyannmarshall.github.io.